Jerry Davis

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jerry-davis-8991641b4/ Email: Jwdavis8589@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://www.silverwindworkshop.com/

SUMMARY

Game Developer with a successfully shipped Game Design commercial product for the popular Dungeons & Dragons virtual tabletop, Roll20. Award-winning Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience working with a large codebase servicing 4.5 million customers and over 65,000 physicians.

EXPERIENCE

Game Designer

Silverwind Workshop

February 2022 - Current

- Independent game design focused on a systems design rework for Dungeons & Dragons 5th Edition via Roll20 Marketplace.
- "The customization of this system has honestly made it hard for me to go back to standard D&D. It honestly impresses me the depth and creativity that is present in this. If more flair and flexibility in combat is what you want, this is for you."

 -User Review for Skills Trees & Leveling Overhaul
- Free demo materials available in portfolio website.
- Drove 100% of game design, testing, user experience, and graphical design.

Senior Associate Developer

Infosys

March 2021 - March 2023

- 100% experience working for BlueShield of California client as a Software Engineer contractor.
- Reduced web application overhead for 50% of pages.
- Developed, bug-fixed, and performed code analysis of codebase used by 1 in 9 Californians.
- Led a team of 5 agile software engineers while providing Knowledge Transfers for Portal Support Team, Urgent Solutions Team, and Junior Associates.

PROJECTS

Black Friday - GameDevTV Game Jam 2024

- Action and Tower Defense hybrid game where you are a retail-worker during Black Friday and must use the store's appliances (towers) to stop customers from reaching your manager to report you. You may also melee customers with the jam's theme, the Last (furniture) Stand.
- Lead game director, game designer, scrum master, product owner, game developer.
- Lead team of 6 interdisciplinary developers using SCRUM methodology.

Cracked Glass – 2nd Place Winner, Figerox Underwater Horror Jam 2024

- Defense and crafting horror game where your submarine is caught in the maw of a giant sea monster. Survive defense waves while repairing the submarine to fend it off temporarily. Between defense rounds, delve into seabed dungeons to gather resources and new weapons to stave off the leviathan's continued onslaught.
- Lead game director, game designer, scrum master, product owner, game developer, and pixel artist.
- Lead team of 3 software engineers through our first game jam using SCRUM methodology, resulting in 1st place in mechanics and 2nd place overall.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Computer Science

Arkansas State University

August 2016 – May 2020

Graduated with Cum Laude.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C#, C++, JavaScript, Java, Python

Hard Skills: Unity, Gamemaker Studio, Git, Jira, Trello, Agile, Scrum Methodology, MS Azure, Systems Design, Game Design, Mathematics, Problem Solving, Debugging

Soft Skills: Communication, Leadership, Positive Attitude, Time Management, Team Player, Teamwork, Critical Thinking